aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these six the brave powers of Dagwon.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 여섯명의 용자 다그온
And now, their new member is Gunkid!
그리고 새로운 동료는, 건키드!
Wh- what the-?
뭐, 뭐야?
What is this place?
여기가 어디지?
To You Who is Going Away
떠나가는 그대에게
Space Spider Pider Seijin
Appears
우주 거미 파이더 성인
등장
Hey, Shin!
여봐, 신!
Let's go to arcade and play a game together!
오락실 가서 한판 하자구
Unfortunately I am busy with a date!
공교롭게도 데이트 때문에 바빠서 말이지
I'll give my love to all the cute girls...
나의 사랑을 이 세상의 귀여운 애들에게...
Wh- who's that?
누, 누구냐, 저 애?
Don't you know? She is...
너 모르냐?
저건 말이지...
a species known as a beautiful girl.
'미소녀'라는 거야
-Um, excuse me.
-Huh?
-저어... 실례합니다
-음?
Is Kazamatsuri in this high school?
이 고등학교에 카자마츠리 군...
-Move!
-비켜~!
-비켜!
Miss, wouldn't you like to talk about love with me?
아가씨, 나와 사랑에 대해 논해 보지 않겠어?
If you have something you don't know, ask me!
모르는 게 있으면 나한테 물어봐
Then do you know Kazamatsuri?
그럼, 카자마츠리 군을 알고 계신가요?
Kazamatsuri?
카자마츠리?
I think I heard that name before.
분명히 어디선가 들어본 듯한...
The reproduction rate of this fungi is...
곰팡이의 번식률은...
Yoku, there's a visitor for you.
요쿠, 손님 데려왔다
Please wait for a moment. I'm busy right now.
기다려 주세요
지금 바빠서요
-Thank you.
-No problem.
-고마워요
-천만에
Yukari Fujii!
후지이 유카리!
Long time no see, Kazamatsuri.
오랜만이야, 카자마츠리 군
So she's Yukari, huh?
유카리인가...
I never thought Yoku knew someone that cute!
요쿠가 아는 사람 중에 저런 귀여운 애가 있었다니...
You haven't changed a bit from middle school.
정말 중학교 때랑 변함이 없구나
Then, would you like to take a look?
저기, 너도 봐 볼래?
Fungi are cute if you observe them!
곰팡이도 관찰해 보면 제법 귀여워
The mechanism of nature is mysterious yet beatuful.
신비하고 아름다운 자연의 메카니즘...
Listen to me. I...
저기 말이야, 나...
Just a moment.
잠깐 기다려
Time to observe caterpillars.
애벌레 관찰 시간이야
How can he observe in a time like this?!
아아~ 이런 때에까지 관찰이냐?
Alright, I'll talk to Yukari instead of Yoku!
좋았어, 내가 요쿠 대신 유카리의 상대를...
I am moving away soon.
나 이번에 이사가
It's so sudden, but I am going to Australia.
갑작스레 말하게 되었지만 오스트레일리아로 가게 됐어
Isn't it awesome?
굉장하지?
Australia? That far away?
오스트레일리아?
그렇게나 멀리?
Then I won't be able to meet you again...
그렇게 되면 역시 못 만나게 될 테니까...
Before going...
그 전에...
But it should feel good!
그치만 좋겠다~
You're going to Australia! Australia!
오스트레일리아야, 오스트레일리아!
It must be full of fun subjects of mother nature!
대자연의 한가운데, 재미있을 것 같은 주제가 한가득 있잖아
It was fun today.
오늘은 즐거웠어
Are you going back already?
에, 벌써 돌아가게?
-Yes. Farewell!
-Hey, Fujii!
-응, 잘 있어
-아앗, 후지이
That's disappointing!
뭐야, 맥빠지는구만
He should be more glad to see her.
좀 더 반가워할 줄 알았는데...
Don't you agree, Shin?
안그래, 신?
Huh? Shin?
어레... 신?
Yukari!
유카리~
-You're...
-Heh!
-당신은...
-야호~
Thanks for guiding me before.
아까 길 안내해 주셔서 고마워요
No need to thank me.
헤헷, 감사할 필요 없어
I'm a best friend of Yoku's anyway!
난 요쿠와 가장 친한 친구니까 말이지
With Kazamatsuri?
카자마츠리 군하고요?
Right! A friend of his is a friend of mine!
그래, 친구의 친구는 이미 친구나 마찬가지!
Therefore... would you like to get some tea with me?
그런 관계로, 지금부터 둘이서 차라도 한 잔 어때?
Missing car case?
자동차 실종 사건?
Right. Recently lots of cars have disappeared.
그래, 최근 며칠간만에 수많은 자동차가 사라지다니
It's a puzzle. A mystery.
수수께끼야, 미스테리야
It is most certainly a weird case.
확실히, 괴 사건이군
I think it went to the space in the secondary dimension.
내 예감으로는 이차원 공간에 빨려들어간 것 같아
That's our Maria! So keen!
과연 마리아 씨구만!
예리합니다요!
He's not here either.
여기도 없네
Where did Shin disappear to?
신 녀석, 어디로 사라진 거야?
What? Did Shin disappear too?
에엣, 신까지 사라진 거야?!
More mysteries.
아아... 갈수록 의문이군
As expected, tea with a beautiful girl is tasty!
역시 미인과 함께 마시는 차는 맛있구만!
Sorry.
미안해
But, Mr. Sawamura, you're completely different from Kazamatsuri, for a friend.
그치만, 사와무라 씨는 카자마츠리 군의 친구 치고는 서로 성격이 전혀 달라서요
I can't imagine Kazamatsuri of middle school being like you.
중학교 시절의 카자마츠리 군으로서는 상상할 수가 없어서...
Hm, I wonder what his middle school life was like.
흐음... 그녀석의 중학교 시절이라니, 대체...
But I can imagine Yukari's middle school life well!
하지만, 유카리의 중학교 시절이라면 상상이 되는걸
You must have been cute back then too!
그때도 귀여웠겠지?
Awesome...
멋지다...
Do you like birds?
새를 좋아하는구나
Yes. I wondered what it would be like to fly in the sky like them ever since I was a child.
응, 저런 식으로 하늘을 날면 어떨까 하고 어렸을 때부터 쭉 생각했어
You're a romanticist, Yukari!
유카리는 몽상가구나
(romanticist -공상가, 몽상가)
When I told this to Kazamatsuri, he talked about
이 이야기를 카자마츠리 군에게 했더니
the requirements for humans to fly are some meters of wings and muscles,
인간이 하늘을 날기 위해서는 몇 미터의 날개와 근육이 필요하다든가
or the process of evolution from dinosaurs to birds all day long.
공룡이 새로 진화하는 과정이라든가 정말, 한참동안 이야기를 들었어
He's a weird guy.
웃기는 녀석이군
Guess what Kazamatsuri gave me as a birthday present that year!
그 해 생일에 카자마츠리 군이 준 선물, 뭐라고 생각해?
Reptilla picture book this thick!
이렇게 두꺼운 파충류 도감이야
He gave you that?
나 참, 그런 걸 선물로 주다니...
He could have given you something more polished!
좀 세련된 선물을 줄 순 없나?
But... it's something that only Kazamatsuri could choose as a present.
하지만... 과연 카자마츠리 군다운 느낌의 선물이어서...
Don't you think so?
그치? 그렇게 생각 안 해?
Yukari...
유카리...
My sense shines on this.
센스가 돋보이는군
I can see Yukari's face when she gets it!
이걸 받은 유카리의 얼굴이 눈에 선하구만~
Yukari!
유카리~
Be careful! This is a precious brooch!
조심해!
이건 귀중한 브로치라구!
Sorry.
죄송합니다
-Oh, you're Shin!
-Yoku?
-뭐야, 신?
-요쿠?
I see it's a seagull.
음... 갈매기군요
Well, for a seagull, its wings are too much deformed, and the vertical positions of the wings as a bird are-
뭐, 갈매기치고는 조금 날개의 과장이 심하지만 조류의 특징으로서는 조금 더 날개의 선단이...
Shut up!
시끄러워!
I don't need your impudent meddling!
시건방진 참견 따윈 필요없어!
I will celebrate my youth with this!
이건 내 청춘을 구가(謳歌)할 거라구
Giving it to a girl as a gift is good too, but shouldn't you better widen your eyesight?
여자애에게 선물하는 것도 좋지만 조금 더 시야를 넓히는 게 좋지 않을까요?
Hmph, don't you say that to me.
흥, 너한테만은 그런 소리 듣고 싶지 않은걸
Wh- what the-?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
Help me!
사, 살려줘!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류
What's going on?
어떻게 된 거야?
A thread?
실?
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Fire En!
파이어 엔!
Darkness is coming, crisis is approaching Earth
어둠이 온다 지구에 위기가 다가온다
You will rise
그대여 일어나라
Transform to Fire En
파이어 엔으로 변신이다
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Go toward the figure of an enemy recklessly
무조건 적을 향하는 그 모습
like the light on a fuse
도화선의 불길처럼
Track down to anywhere
어디까지나 밀어붙이는 거야
A formidable opponent in the fighting spirit
강적에 투지를 불태워
Go increase your power
파워를 올려 상대해라
Merging Fusion! Dag Fire!
융합합체! 다그 파이어!
Fight! Shatter! Their ambitions!
쳐라! 때려부셔라! 녀석들의 야망
Make them regret coming to Earth
지구에 온 것을 후회하게 만들어 주어라
Run! Strike! With the overflowing youth
달려라! 쳐라! 넘쳐흐르는 젊음과
Go with the strength of flame, dear invincible fighter
불꽃의 힘을 품은 무적의 파이터
Let's go over the clouds.
구름 위로 올라가자
Look, Ryu!
봐, 류!
That is...!
저건...?!
Fight! Shatter! Their ambitions!
쳐라! 때려부셔라! 녀석들의 야망
Make them regret coming to Earth
지구에 온 것을 후회하게 만들어 주어라
Aim! Shoot sharply! With the overflowing youth
노려라! 저격해라! 넘쳐흐르는 젊음과
A spider thread!
거미줄이야!
Go with the might of flame, dear invincible Wing Shot!
불꽃의 위력을 담은 무적의 윙 샷
Reptilla Picture Book
파충류 도감
Farewell to you guys too.
너희들과도 작별이구나
Shin! Yoku! An emergency situation emerged in Hakkaku city!
신, 요쿠! 핫카쿠 시에서 긴급 사태가 발생했어!
Is it an alien from Sargasso?
사르갓소의 우주인이냐?!
Fujii lives in Hakkaku city!
핫카쿠 시라면, 분명히 후지이가 살고 있는 마을입니다!
What? Yukari does?!
뭐야?! 유카리가?!
Damn that Sargasso's alien!
에잇, 사르갓소의 우주인 녀석!
Don't forget! There are people down there! Don't attack thoughtlessly!
알겠어?
저 밑에는 사람이 있어 섣불리 공격하지마
I can't take it anymore!
더이상 못 참겠어!
I'll cut down its threads!
저녀석의 거미줄, 내가 끊어주마!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체
(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Lian!
라이안!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
Wh- what?!
아, 아니?!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Armor!
다그 아머
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!
That's as far as you go, spider alien!
거기까지다, 거미 우주인!
Dag Armor! Dag Wing!
다그 아머, 다그 윙!
Please be safe, Yukari!
어떻게든 무사해 다오, 유카리!
Let's go!
간다!
Just a moment!
기다리세요!
If we go like this, we're going to end up like Fire Dagwon and the others!
이대로 덤벼봤자, 다른 다그온들처럼 되고 말아요!
Bu- but...
그, 그치만...
If we don't do something the result will be same!
이대로 있어도 결과는 마찬가지라구!
I know!
알고 있어요!
I see! That's it!
그렇군, 저거였어!
Shin! Protect me!
신, 엄호해 주세요
Hey! Yoku!
이, 이봐! 요쿠!
Shudder runs over the beautiful planet
아름다운 행성에 전율이 흐른다
Like I can defy you! You could have told me your intention though-
별 수 없구만!
뭔 생각을 하는 건지...
Feeling the moment the storm is coming on
폭풍이 오는 순간을 느끼며
Even though it is a thread made by anticipating our attacks...
공격을 계산해서 만든 거미줄이지만...
Just like a hero inside is awakening
마음 속에서 깨어나는 영웅과 같이
Let's go! Let's fly away! Don't look back again!
가자! 날아가자! 뒤돌아보지 마라!
If I manage to attack one weak spot...
급소 한 곳만 공격한다면!
N- no!
아, 아뿔싸!
Dagwon... Keep on shining!! Dagwon!
다그온... 계속 빛나라! 다그온!
What?
아니!?
Get it on! It's the name of peace to love
지켜라! 사랑해야 할 평화의 이름
Dagwon... You know we are Dagwon!
다그온... 우리는 다그온!
Crystal Cutter!
크리스탈 커터!
Get it on... Nobody can take our dreams away!
우리 꿈은 그 누구도 가져갈 수 없어!
Oh, please if you wanna win trust and courage
신뢰와 우정을 얻고 싶다면 꼭
Leave the rest to us!
이렇게 되면, 이쪽이 유리하다구!
Believe in believe in just believe in friendship, powerfully
믿어라 믿어라 우정을 믿어라 강력하게
Do the right thing forever, don't be afraid of damage
피해에 개의치 않고 끝까지 옳은 것을 해라
Go ahead, go ahead, just go ahead for the future to dream
나아가, 나아가, 쭉 나아가라! 꿈 속의 미래를 위해!
Gunkid!
건키드!
Oh, please if you wanna win trust and courage
신뢰와 우정을 얻고 싶다면 꼭
Let's go! Infinity Cannon!
간다, 무한포(無限砲)!
Believe in believe in just believe in friendship, powerfully
믿어라 믿어라 우정을 믿어라 강력하게
Do the right thing forever, don't be afraid of damage
피해에 개의치 않고 끝까지 옳은 것을 해라
Fire!
파이어!
Go ahead, go ahead, just go ahead for the future to dream
나아가, 나아가, 쭉 나아가라! 꿈 속의 미래를 위해!
Good to know you're safe.
무사해서 다행이야
Fujii, hang in there!
후지이, 정신차려
Kazamatsuri...
카자마츠리 군...
Don't be sick and live well after moving too.
이사 가서도 몸 건강히 지내
Thank you. You too, Kazamatsuri.
응, 카자마츠리 군도...
Yukari, um...
유카리, 저기...
-Sawamura...
-Hm?
- 사와무라...
- 응?
Sawamura, you too, don't be sick!
사와무라도 건강히 지내
Farewell.
안녕...
Farewell...
Give this to her for me.
이거, 주고 와
-Huh?
-Hurry up!
- 에?
- 얼른
What a wonderful sunshine
정말 아름다운 햇빛이야
Just like a brand new day
마치 새로운 날처럼
Fujii...
후지이...
silent afternoon that I wouldn't expect
생각치도 못했던 조용한 오후
Kazamatsuri.
카자마츠리 군
Uh, um...
저, 저기... 그러니까...
This...
이, 이거...
I was singing to myself
나에게 노래부르고 있었어
passing through the gentle hills
조용한 언덕을 지나가며
Are you giving that to me?
이걸 나한테...?
then I came here to see the clear blue ocean
그리고 맑고 푸른 바다를 보러 여기에 왔어
Yes. That is... Shin's...
응, 그게...
신이 말이지...
The ripples are lapping
잔물결이 밀려와
Thank you.
고마워...
I know, endless melody
알아, 끝없는 멜로디
Uh, you should know...
저, 저기...
So it seems to keep its shape forever
그 모양 영원히 계속되도록
Farewell, Kazamatsuri.
안녕, 카자마츠리 군...
I'll be following the fantastic world
굉장한 세상에 살아갈 거야
Sparking in the distance
멀리서 반짝이던
Was Yukari happy?
유카리, 기뻐했지?
It's a prism in the wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Hey, are you listening to me? Yoku?
이봐. 듣고 있어, 요쿠?
I'll be following the fantastic world
굉장한 세상에 살아갈 거야
Hey, Yoku! Yoku!
이봐, 요쿠
요쿠!
Sparking in the distance
멀리서 반짝이던
It's a prism in the wind
바람 속의 프리즘
I guess it'll be alright.
별 수 없군
I... am Yoku's best friend!
나, 요쿠와 가장 친한 친구니까
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
A UFO has appeared and it keeps digging holes in beaches.
해안에 나타나 차례차례 구멍을 파는 거대한 UFO
-What is it doing anyway?
-It's looking for Ladonpa's box.
-대체 녀석은 무슨 짓을 하는 거야?
-라돈파의 상자를 찾고 있는 거야
What the heck is Ladonpa's box?
라돈파의 상자? 그게 뭐냐?
It is trying to bring the downfall to humankind by using that.
녀석은 그걸 이용해서 전 인류를 멸망으로 몰아넣을 셈이야
What? The downfall of humankind with only one box?!
에에? 상자 하나로 인류 멸망?
Right. When that box opens, something unimaginable will happen!
그래. 그 상자가 열리는 순간, 무서운 일이 벌어진다!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A Shudder Over the Blue Planet
다음회 용자지령 다그온
푸른 별의 전율
I will stop the box from opening no matter what!
내가 반드시 막아 보이겠다!
A Shudder
Over the Blue Planet
푸른 별의 전율